School of Engineering and Applied Science Records, 1884-2017: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 1: Dean of the School of Engineering and Applied Science, 1896-2016 September 13; 149.37 linear feet 121 boxes Digital Folders: 97, Digital Files: 2,135 73,438 email messages
  - Subseries 1B: Joseph C. Elgin, 1922-1972; 97.92 linear feet 79 boxes
    - Chemical Engineering Processes, 1947 February-1959; 4 folders
      - Podbielniak Incorporated Brochure Number 10, circa 1950s; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 34)
      - The Extraction of Cobalt from Nickel in a Pulse Column, 1952; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - Division of Industrial Engineering and Chemistry, 1948-1952; 2 folders
      - 1949-1952, 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Symposia Plans, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - United States Rubber Reclaiming, 1951; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - National Research Council, 1951; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Elgin, J. C., 1948-1953; more than 2 folders
      - Personal, 1951-1952; 2 folders (Box 42, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Miscellaneous - A, H, N, P, S, T, 1948-1953; 6 folders (Box 42, Folder 7 to 12)
    - Calco Chemical Company - Consulting, 1947-1951; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Plastics Program, 1943 August-1948; 2 folders
      - 1943 August-1945 June, 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - 1946-1948, 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Library, 1945-1953; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - University of Minnesota, 1947-1949; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - National Science Foundation, 1953; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Office of Naval Research, 1948-1952; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Patent Policies, 1944-1952; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Wetted Wall G. A. System Correspondence, 1952; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Personal Correspondence - Dean Appointment, 1954 April; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Kokatnur, V. R, 1945-1946; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-1954; 14 folders
      - K, 1948-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - Mc, 1946-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - M, 1947-1953; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - N, 1952-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - O, 1946-1952; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - P, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Q, 1950; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - R, 1935-1953; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - S, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - T, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 18)
      - U, 1948-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - V, 1951-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 20)
      - W, 1948-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - X-Y-Z, 1949; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Celanese Corporation of America Chemical Division: "Perforated Plate Distillation Columns", circa 1950; portion of 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Consultations and Bylaws Committee - Frederick Papers, 1952; portion of 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - "Countercurrent Flow of Particles through Continuous Fluids - Pressure Drop in Spray-Type Towers", 1949; portion of 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Notes and Reference for Paper in Educating Chemical Engineers of the Future, 1936-1952; portion of 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Task Force on Engineering Manpower, 1951-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - Chicago Alumni Meeting, 1952-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Brochures, Magazine Articles, Publications, Correspondence, Papers, Etc, 1952-1954; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Chicago Alumni Talk, 1952; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - Liquid-Liquid Extractor Design, circa 1950; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 29)
    - General Research Topics, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 30)
    - Hagerty, James C., Press Release, 1960 November 20; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Winterkorn, Hans F, 1943-1954; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Engineering Building - Correspondence, 1924-1928; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation, 1957-1966; 3 folders
      - 1957-1966, 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Proposal, 1960 January 14; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Proposal Copy, 1959 December; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Bridge, Alan G, 1961-1965; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Chemical Engineering, 1965; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - American Society for Engineering Education Goals of Engineering Education - Reports, 1964-1970; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Admissions Office, 1963-1965; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Advisory Council Briefing, 1963; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Gifts to Princeton, 1963-1968; 5 folders
      - 1963-1964, 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - 1964-1965, 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - 1965-1966, 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - 1966-1967, 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - 1967-1968, 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - Advisory Committee, Program of Student Evaluation of Instruction, 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Chemical Engineering Department, 1967; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation - Engineering Faculty Questionnaire, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Controller - Miscellaneous, 1962-1967; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Minutes - Clerk of the Faculty, 1966-1968; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Committee on the Graduate School - Report to the University Faculty, 1968 June 3; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Weaver, Robert Edgar Coleman, 1955-1960; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation Fellowships - Alternates, 1961; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Civil and Geological Engineering, 1967; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Commencement, 1961 June 13-1964 June 16; 3 folders
      - 1961 June 13, 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - 1963 June 18, 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - 1964 June 16, 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1955-1968; 3 folders
      - 1955-1960, 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - 1960-1963, 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - 1966-1968, 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - American Society for Engineering Education, 1967-1968; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Faculty Minutes of Meetings, 1966-1968; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Advisory Council - Correspondence, Minutes, 1960-1966; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Dean of the College, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Advisory Council - List of Members, 1960-1966; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Summary of Faculty Professional Activities, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - American Society for Engineering Education Engineering Degrees, Committee on Review of, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - Secretary's Notebook, 1952-1963; 5 folders
      - 1959-1960, 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - 1958-1959, 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - 1957-1958, 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - 1962-1963, 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - 1952-1957, 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Committees - Engineering, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Clerk of the University, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - American Society for Engineering Education - Financial Policy Committee, 1967-1969; 2 folders
      - 1967-1969, 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Meeting, Lansing, Michigan, 1967-1969; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Determination of Academic Standing - CODAS, 1962-1966; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Engineering Science Seminars - Ad Hoc Committee, 1959 October; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - ESSO Research and Engineering Company, 1964-1966; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Dean of the College, 1965-1966; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Chemical Engineering - Visiting Faculty, Research Appointments, 1965-1968; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 14)
      [restricted until 2043]
    - Aerospace and Mechanical Sciences - Correspondence: Faculty Appointments, Promotions, Etc, 1962-1968; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Faculty Committees - Engineering, 1956-1967; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Fellowships, 1930-1963; 9 folders
      - Radio Corporation of America, 1952-1961; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - Standard Oil Foundation Incorporated, 1955-1959; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 18)
      - Sayre, 1947 July 1; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 19)
      - Electrical Engineering - Schlumberger Foundation, 1960; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 20)
      - Shell Development Company, 1955-1959; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 21)
      - Schlumberger Foundation Fellowship, 1960; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 22)
      - Union Carbide (Plastics), 1957-1962; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 23)
      - Wallace, 1930-1949; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 24)
      - Xerox Fellowship, 1963; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Electrical Engineering Department, 1963-1965; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Advisory Council Correspondence, Member Lists, Minutes of Meetings, 1963-1965; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Warren K. Lewis Awards Committee, 1964; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - American Society for Engineering Education, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Council, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - American Institute of Chemical Engineers, 1959-1965; 4 folders
      - Awards Committee, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Professional Development Committee, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Professional Development Subcommittee on Ethics, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - General Correspondence, 1959-1963; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Faculty, Clerk of the University, 1962-1965; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Research Corporation, 1964-1966; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Engineering Computer Administrative Committee, 1958-1962; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - ESSO Education Foundation, 1958-1961; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Plastics Advisory Committee, 1961-1965; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Advisory Council - Mechanical Engineering, 1960-1963; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - School of Engineering and Applied Sciences - Executive Committee, 1969-1971; 3 folders
      - 1969-1970, 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Minutes, 1969-1970; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Active, 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Committee on the Freshman Year, 1967-1968; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Secretary's Notebook, 1960-1965; 4 folders
      - 1964-1965, 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - 1963-1964, 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 19)
      - 1961-1962, 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 20)
      - 1960-1961, 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - American Society for Engineering Education, 1959-1963; 3 folders
      - Correspondence, 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, Bulletins, Bylaws, Minutes, 1962; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - National Legislation Committee, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - American Institute of Chemical Engineers, 1958-1964; 3 folders
      - Correspondence, Brochures, Etc, 1963; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Awards Committee, 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - W. K. Lewis Award Subcommittees, 1958-1964; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Appointments, Recommendations, 1949-1961; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 7)
      [restricted until 2036]
    - Engineering Faculty - Minutes, 1955-1961; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Aeronautical Engineering - Correspondence, Recommendations Etc, 1956-1963; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Contributions and Prospective Donors to Engineering School, 1958-1959; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report to the President, 1970-1972; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Goheen, Robert F., 1955-1971; 7 folders
      - 1955-1960, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - 1960-1961, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - 1961-1962, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - 1962-1963, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - 1963, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - 1964-1965, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - 1965-1971, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Coyle, Daniel D. - President's Office, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Dodds, Harold W., 1953-1955; 2 folders
      - 1953-1955, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - 1955, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Brown, Dean J. Douglas, 1951-1961; 4 folders
      - 1954-1959, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - 1954-1957, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - 1951-1952, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - 1959-1961, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Dean of the Faculty, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Graduate School Office, 1954-1963; 4 folders
      - 1959-1961, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Other, 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - 1958-1960, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - 1954-1957, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Taylor, Hugh Stott - Dean of Graduate School, 1951-1960; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Engineering Quadrangle Project Committee IV Whitwell Memos, 1956-1963; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Perspectives, 1965; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Dean Greeve - Photo, 1940; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Engineering Quadrangle - Architect Photos, 1959; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Engineering Quadrangle Architects, 1956-1963; 3 folders
      - 1960-1963, 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - 1956-1961, 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - 1960, 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Fund Campaign - $53,000,000 Capital, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Engineering Quadrangle Gifts, 1959 November; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Material for Florida Trip - AVD, 1960; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Engineering Quadrangle Brochure, 1956-1963; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Development Office, 1956-1962; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Engineering Quadrangle - Naming, Princeton List, Room Memorial List, 1958-1962; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - The Secondary Schools Matter - Engineering Quadrangle Conference on Engineering Education, 1961-1964; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Princeton Alumni, 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Minutes, Engineering Quadrangle Project Committee, 1956-1962; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Construction by Crow, 1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Crow Construction Company, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Engineering Quadrangle, 1955-1963; 17 folders
      - Faculty Committee Memos and Notices of Meetings, 1956-1958; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Surveys of Other Institutions, 1956-1959; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Dedication Ceremony, 1962 October 13; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Dedication Committee, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Fund Possibilities, 1957-1963; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Dedication Invitees, 1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Moving Operations, EQPC, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Planning Committee 1, 1955; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Plans and Layout, 1955-1958; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Dedication - List of those Attending, 1962 October 13; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Press Cuttings, Releases, 1962 October; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Dedication, 1962 October 13; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Planning Committee, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Whitwell Memos, 1955-1960; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Memos - Our Needs, 1955-1958; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Engineering Quadrangle Project Committee III - Whitwell Memos, 1957-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Princeton University Fund Material, 1949-1953; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Aeronautical Engineering - Project Proposals, 1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Final Report on the Princeton Capital Campaign, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - "A New Approach to Engineering at Princeton", circa 1956; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Aeronautical Engineering Research Personnel, 1960-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Engineers Joint Council Correspondence, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Rheinstein, Robert, 1951-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Joseph Henry Centre, 1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - Newcomen Society, 1957 June; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - General Correspondence, 1954; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - President's Report, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - President's Report, 1961 September 6; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - American Society for Engineering Education - Administrative Officers and Department Heads List, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Appointments, 1957-1962; 9 folders
      - Geological Research, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 33)
      - Plastics Research, 1957-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 34)
      - Electrical Engineering, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 35)
      - Electrical Engineering Research, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 36)
      - Civil Engineering Assistants in Instruction, 1958-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 37)
      - Civil Engineering Research, 1960-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 38)
        [restricted until 2037]
      - Chemical Engineering Research, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 39)
      - Mechanical Engineering, 1958-1961; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 40)
      - Mechanical Engineering Research, 1960-1962; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Executive Committee, 1946 January 29-1957; 8 folders
      - Minutes, 1946 January 29-1957; 6 folders
        - 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 1)
        - 1955-1956, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - 1949-1954, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 3)
        - 1946 January 29-1949 June 6, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 4)
        - 1953-1954, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 5)
        - 1954-1955, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Memoranda, 1951-1955; 2 folders
        - 1951-1952, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 7)
        - To Department Chairmen, 1952-1955; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Faculty, 1946-1967; 14 folders
      - Notices, 1951-1954; 2 folders
        - 1951-1952, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 9)
        - 1953-1954, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Announcements and Agenda, 1954-1958; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Committees, 1955-1957; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Memoranda, 1952-1957; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - Departmental Representatives, 1954-1957; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - Executive Memoranda, 1955-1957; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Minutes, 1946-1967; 6 folders
        - 1954-1955, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 16)
        - 1946-1948, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 17)
        - 1949-1951, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 18)
        - 1952-1954, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 19)
        - 1952-1953, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 20)
        - 1966-1967, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 21)
      - Vital Statistics, 1957; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Economics - Engineering, 1957-1962; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Electives for Engineering Students, 1962-1967; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Committee on the Basic Engineering Program, 1954-1966; 4 folders
      - 1963-1966, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 25)
      - 1962-1963, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 26)
      - 1957-1959, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 27)
      - 1954-1956, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - Committee on the Freshman Year, 1964-1967; 2 folders
      - 1966-1967, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 29)
      - 1964-1966, 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Freshman Appointments with Advisers and Deans, Fall Term, 1968; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - United States Government Awards, Fulbright Act, 1955-1957; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - Dean of the Faculty Correspondence, 1969-1971; 1966-1968; 2 folders (Box 54, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Brown, J. Douglas, 1946-1963; 8 folders
      - 1962-1963, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - 1961-1963, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - 1955-1956, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - 1949-1950, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - 1950-1951, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - 1952-1954, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - 1946-1949, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - 1954-1955, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1946-1961; 9 folders
      - 1946-1954, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Executive Committee, 1946-1950; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 13)
      - Agenda, 1954-1957; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 14)
      - 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 15)
      - Executive Committee, 1957-1958; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 16)
      - 1955-1956, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 17)
      - Agenda, Faculty and Executive Committee, 1959; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 18)
      - Agenda, Executive, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Executive Committee - Notices, Memos, Business, 1959-1962; 2 folders
      - 1961-1962, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 20)
      - 1959-1961, 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - Pre-Fall Term Talks, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Faculty, Memos to, 1960-1962; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - Chemical Engineering - Former Faculty Members and Research Personnel, 1963-1968; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Water Resources Conference, 1966; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Nassau Club - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1958-1959; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - National Alumni Meeting, 1959; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1954-1956; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - National Alumni Association Conferences, 1957 April 10-12; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - National Research Council, 1954-1960; 5 folders
      - 1957-1958, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Division of Chemistry and Chem. Tech, 1957-1960; 2 folders
        - 1958-1960, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 8)
        - 1957-1958, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - 1954-1957, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - 1956, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - National Science Foundation, 1954-1960; 3 folders
      - 1958-1960, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - 1954-1957, 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - Special Commission, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - National Society for Professional Engineers, 1958-1963; 2 folders
      - 1958-1960, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - 1961-1963, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - National Research Council, 1958-1961; 2 folders
      - 1958-1961, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Division of Chemistry and Chemistry Tech, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - National Science Foundation, 1955-1962; 4 folders
      - 1957-1958, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - 1961-1962, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - 1960-1961, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - 1955, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - New Jersey Conference on Utilization of Engineers, 1958 April; 2 folders (Box 56, Folder 9 to 10)
    - New Jersey Society for Professional Engineers, 1949-1969; 2 folders
      - 1955-1969, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - 1949-1955, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Newell, James P, 1952-1963; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - New Jersey State Board of Professional Engineers and Surveyors, 1953; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - New York State Education Department - Registration, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Nichols, C. W, 1960; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Nikolsky, Alexander A, 1949-1960; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Nuclear Reactor Management Ad Hoc Committee, 1955-1961; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Program of Nuclear Studies, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - 'N' Miscellaneous, 1956-1963; 2 folders
      - 1962-1963, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 20)
      - 1956-1961, 1 folder (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratories, 1951-1956; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 1)